<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title><![CDATA[Kaleem Clarkson]]></title>
    <link href="http://kaleemclarkson.com/blog/tags/personal branding.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="http://kaleemclarkson.com/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-04T08:32:36+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://kaleemclarkson.com/blog/tags/personal branding.xml</id>
            <author>
            <name><![CDATA[Kaleem Clarkson]]></name>                    </author>
        <generator uri="http://sculpin.io/">Sculpin</generator>
            <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Year with a New outLook on Personal Branding]]></title>
            <link href="http://kaleemclarkson.com/blog/2015/01/05/A-New-Year-with-a-New-outLook-on-Personal-Branding"/>
            <updated>2015-01-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
            <id>http://kaleemclarkson.com/blog/2015/01/05/A-New-Year-with-a-New-outLook-on-Personal-Branding</id>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>New Years is by far the best holiday. Why you ask? Well for starters there is neither the stress of having to purchase gifts, nor the fortitude it takes to prepare a large meal for thirty, and its the only holiday which comes to mind that every country, race, religious or political affiliation celebrate. But for me the icing on the cake is the euphoria of creativity, potential, and optimism that is shared by millions all over the world.</p>

<p>In a recent <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/louise-firth-campbell-/post_6564_b_4602842.html">study by University of Scranton</a> it was determined that only <b>1 in 8</b> people will keep their new year resolutions. While the statistics are against us for following through on resolutions the more encouraging and exciting statistic showed that "people who make a New Year's resolution are 10 times more likely to change their lives than those who don't." So like someone in my family used to say about the lottery, &ldquo;if you don&rsquo;t play, you can&rsquo;t win.&rdquo;</p>

<p>My hope is that by writing down my resolutions for the world to see, maybe just maybe one of you who reads this will make me accountable to be that 1 person out of 8 that succeeds. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<h3>My 2015 New Year Resolutions</h3>

<h4><ul>
  <li>
    Build a new look for my personal brand
  </li>
  <li>
    Become a better writer and presenter
  </li>
  <li>
    Share my knowledge on a consistent basis
  </li>
</ul></h4>

<h3>Build a New Look for my Personal Brand.</h3>

<p>As C-suite executive job strategist, <a href="http://executivecareerbrand.com/the-new-10-step-executive-personal-branding-worksheet/">Meg Guiseppi summarizes it</a>, &nbsp;your personal brand is a combination of your attributes, values, strengths and passions that help stakeholders determine if they should do business with you. &nbsp;As a co-founder of <a href="http://blendmeinc.com">blend me, Inc</a>., an internal marketing and HR consulting company, I, like other creatives, fail to carve out enough time to build our personal brands up as we would for our clients.</p>

<p><b>Action:</b> Revitalize my personal brand with a consistent design. &nbsp;Use this website to learn new web technologies.</p>

<h3>Become a Better Writer and Presenter</h3>

<p>The work we do at <a href="http://blendmeinc.com">blend me, Inc</a> primarily focuses on teleworking best practices, much of the research emphasizes the continuous improvement of written and oral communications. For me, all through school from middle school to college, I was terrified of the English classes that were graded based on punctuation and grammar. And to this day submitting an article for review puts me in a red correction pen nightmare.</p>

<p>To the contrary public speaking has always come naturally and something that I have excelled at &nbsp;but to produce an engaging and educational presentation is a skill that takes years of practice and one I hope to improve one.</p>

<p><b>Action:</b> Find a mentor who will help review my posts and presentations. &nbsp;</p>

<h3>Share My Knowledge on a Regular Basis</h3>

<p>One way to fully enhance a skill is through repetition and trial and error. &nbsp;So to become a better writer and presenter it is imperative that I am able to share my knowledge on a regular basis in in multiple formats that fosters discussion. &nbsp;Through discussion and debate I hope gain more insight from industry leaders that will help improve my ability to articulate my views clearly and concisely.</p>

<p><b>Action:</b> Post an article at least once a month. Present 6 times in 2015.</p>

<p>I hope that you enjoyed this post and you find some of this information useful to you. &nbsp;I will continue blogging on various topics ranging from entrepreneurship, &nbsp;front-end web development, Drupal, leadership, teleworking tools and strategies. If you have any thoughts or suggestions for me please let me know by contacting me or making a comment below.</p>

<p>Thanks again and happy New Year!!!</p>

<p>Kaleem</p>
]]></content>
        </entry>
    </feed>